

DLB 625G, 34 Renfrew Rd, HKBU, Hong Kong csxyzhang@comp.hkbu.edu.hk in xinyi-zhang-hkbu

PhD student in the Department of Computer Science at Hong Kong Baptist University with experience in designing and implementing various high-performance, secure database and blockchain systems.

# **PROFESSIONAL** EXPERIENCE

### Hong Kong Baptist University Ph.D. Candidate

Hong Kong Sep 2021 – Present

• Advisor: Prof. Jianliang Xu

- Designed novel algorithms for data federation to support efficient and secure query processing in a wide range of systems.
- Resulted to research paper published in top-tier and conferences.

## Huazhong University of Science and Technology Core Member

Wuhan, China

*May* 2019 – *Feb* 2020

- Design a fast consensus algorithm of blockchain combining SDN, dPOS and PBFT consensus algorithm.
- Build a practical blockchain system for ASTRI as a integrity-assured record for their public distributed database.

### Huazhong University of Science and Technology **Core Member**

Wuhan, China

Oct 2019 - Apr 2021

· Research and implement the Algorand consensus algorithm to verify its feasibility for ASTRI's BFC 2.0 system.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Hong Kong Baptist University

Hong Kong

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Sep 2021 - Present

Advisor: Prof. Jianliang Xu

## Huazhong University of Science and Technology

Wuhan, China

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics & Information Engineering

Sep 2017 - Jun 2021

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Rust, C/C++, Golang, Java, Python, Matlab, LATEX, Bash

Tools Docker, Vim, Git, macOS, Linux

Languages English, Mandarin

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Oblivious query processing for data federation and outsourcing cloud computing.
- Scalable secure query processing for vector database based on Trusted Execution Environment.

## SELECTED **PUBLICATIONS**

1. **Z. Xinyi**, W. Qichen, X. Cheng, P. Yun, and J. Xu, "FedKNN: Secure federated k-nearest neighbor search," in Proceedings of the 2024 ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data (SIGMOD '24), Santiago, Chile, Jun. 2024, Full Paper.

#### **AWARDS**

- · College Academic Excellence Scholarship, Huazhong University of Science and Technology 2018, 2021
- First Prize of ADI SDR Cup, Huazhong University of Science and Technology & ADI 2019
- Excellent Teaching Assistant Performance Award, Hong Kong Baptist University 2022, 2023 2024
- RPg Research Performance Award, Hong Kong Baptist University
- ACM SIGMOD 2024 Student Travel Award 2024